<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syllabus on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Syllabus on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo a combination of &#39;museum&#39; by iconsphere and &#39;computer&#39; by Chunk Icons, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 14:09:21 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>A clever bit of visual juxtaposition. Yes&amp;hellip;? Anyone&amp;hellip;?
(Photos by Scott Web https://unsplash.com/photos/ab80p262fFM and Ilya Pavlov https://unsplash.com/photos/OqtafYT5kTw )
HIST4916a Museums and Digital History How do museums and other organizations in the ‘GLAM’ sector (galleries, libraries, archives, museums) keep track of their collections? To what purpose? What might happen if we release these collections into the wild (via the internet)? If we mash these collections together what might we see, and why might it matter?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions How do institutions in the GLAM sector use digital media to support their missions?
Do digital techs push us towards particular voices in GLAM materials?
Can/do digital techs in the service of GLAM harm different communities? And if so, how? And what can we do about it?
Where are the new frontiers in CHI and GLAM?
This course is an opportunity to explore these questions; I do not know the answers!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. A GLAM Workbench</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-glamworkbench/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-glamworkbench/</guid>
        <description>Tangible Output of this Class Each of you will produce a computational notebook - a kind of website that has code within it that can be run, together with text and images describing what&amp;rsquo;s going on - that is focussed on the Ottawa GLAM scene.
All of these notebooks will be gathered together by me into an &amp;lsquo;Ottawa GLAM Workbench&amp;rsquo; (taking our cue from the inspiring work of Tim Sherratt and his GLAM Workbench on Australian and New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s cultural heritage).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Course Schedule</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-schedule/</guid>
        <description>Check out the weekly instructions for detailed guidance for what you should be doing each week.
I estimate that the technical aspects of this course (the computational notebooks) will take about 17 hours over the duration of the course; see the weekly breakdown at the Sequence of Technical Work page.
TL;DR Remember to join our discord so we can actually have some social contact and remember that other breathing human beings are part of this course!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. You grade emerges from the following elements.
  Discussion Leaders. Each student will be responsible to &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; certain readings. Page prep involves:
 Creating the Reading Overview: a brief overview page note attached to the assigned reading using Hypothes.is page notes Creating the Reading Pre-seed: at least five rich/deep annotations on your chosen readings/materials (five total, not five per document) In the relevant week, when the other students read the papers, the student responsible for &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; will engage and respond to the annotations/responses of their peers in such a fashion as to dig deeper into the topic at hand see the guidance note for more information    Collaborative Readers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>9. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/9-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/9-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at https://github.com/shawngraham/hist4916.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>