<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Syllabus on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Syllabus on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 14:09:21 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>HIST4916a Museums and Digital History How do museums and other organizations in the ‘GLAM’ sector (galleries, libraries, archives, museums) keep track of their collections? To what purpose? What might happen if we release these collections into the wild (via the internet)? If we mash these collections together what might we see, and why might it matter? Where are the dangers - and to whom could it be dangerous?
What is Cultural Heritage Informatics?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions text to be added
This course is a formalized exploration of these questions; I do not know the answers! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to figure these out with you.
Nb The process of teaching is also a process of collaboration between me and you. Sometimes -and we&amp;rsquo;re expecting this, you and I- things won&amp;rsquo;t work as we expect; tech might break; the world might impinge too much. We will adapt accordingly. Remember: the grade in this course is a function of your process and your evolution, so adapting and thinking through the implications of when things don&amp;rsquo;t go according to plan is, in fact, according to plan.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. Course Schedule</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</guid>
        <description>** to be figured out **
 Jan 6 term begins  Select your topics &amp;amp; get your &amp;lsquo;chi&amp;rsquo; lab (Hypothesis, Github, Discord) set up
 Wk 1 - Jan 11  Foundations 1 Building 1  Basic digital skills     Wk 2 - Jan 18  Foundations 2 Building 2  OZGlam Workbench     Wk 3 - Jan 25  Representations 1 Building 3  Introduction to Jupyter Notebooks     Wk 4 - Feb 1  Representations 2 Building 4  National Library of Scotland Jupyter Notebooks     Wk 5 - Feb 8  Representations 3 Building 5  GLAMorous Ottawa Your first notebook SWOT of Ottawa: What kinds of things could you do?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. Outputs to be added
  Discussion Leaders. Each student will be responsible to &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; cetain readings. Page prep involves:
 Creating the Reading Overview: a brief overview page note attached to the assigned reading using Hypothes.is page notes Creating the Reading Pre-seed: at least five rich annotations on the assigned readings In the relevant week, when the other students read the papers, the student responsible for &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; will engage and respond to the annotations of their peers in such a fashion as to dig deeper into the topic at hand    Collaborative Readers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at [https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908](https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>