<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DHMuse on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DHMuse on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Visualization</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 3.3 Computational Creativity Compton, Kate. ‘Generominos’ http://www.galaxykate.com/generominos/
Weinard, Chad. 2019. Data as Medium. https://medium.com/@caw_/data-as-medium-361814dba6a9
Whitelaw, Mitchell. 2014. GENERATIVE HERITAGE - NOTES ON SUCCESSION the teeming void https://teemingvoid.blogspot.com/2014/12/generative-heritage-notes-on-succession.html
Woolf, Max. 2019. Experiments with Making Convincing AI-Generated Fake News https://minimaxir.com/2019/09/ctrl-fake-news/
Issue 44. Digital Creativity in Archaeology Internet Archaeology http://intarch.ac.uk/journal/issue44/
Each reading is &amp;lsquo;seeded&amp;rsquo; with annotations by this week&amp;rsquo;s Discussion Leader; some of the annotations may contain video from the Discussion Leader directing you to pay attention to particular issues or ideas.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Case Studies</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read No readings this week. However, look at the rich body of annotation you have. Use the readings and the annotations to help structure and support your Notebook case study.
Do  Write your case study that the other thing  With tech work, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come together in about 30 minutes, it won&amp;rsquo;t come in an hour. So take a break.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CHI &amp; Money</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we consider how to measure, why, and why it matters
 Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 4.1 Budgeting and Bookkeeping Skinner, Sarah J., Robert B. Ekelund, and John D. Jackson. “Art Museum Attendance, Public Funding, and the Business Cycle.” The American Journal of Economics and Sociology 68, no. 2 (2009): 491-516. www.jstor.org/stable/27739781.
Toepler, Stefan. “Caveat Venditor? Museum Merchandising, Nonprofit Commercialization, and the Case of the Metropolitan Museum in New York.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Our Own Adventure</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</guid>
        <description>I wanted this course to be about exploration and figuring out what this field, CHI, meant for this sector, GLAM. As we built this course in the fall, I realized I was making a huge mistake. It was too controlled. Too rigid. Too much about me. When we go to a museum, library, gallery, or archive&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s all about you, and your exploration. That&amp;rsquo;s how meaning emerges, right? So we tried to come up with a way for you to set the agenda and still meet the learning goals.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engagement</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we develop our own cultural heritage informatics infrastructure and explore the ways such infrastructure permits research and creativity
 Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 3.1 Social Media &amp;amp; Audience Research, Ethics &amp;amp; Practice Byrd-McDevitt, Lori. 2019. “Reimagining Social Influencers through an Invitation Culture” in Humanizing the Digital https://ad-hoc-museum-collective.github.io/humanizing-the-digital/chapters/3/
Hooper-Greenhill, Eileen. 2008. “Studying Visitors” in Sharon Macdonald, ed. ‘Companion to Museum Studies’.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we lay the groundwork for what this course will explore, its larger contexts, and what the major research questions are.
 Goals for this week  Get up and running with Hypothesis, Discord, and Github Understand what this course is about Start thinking about your goals for this course  This week is about reading the syllabus and understanding what is expected of you in this course. Get Hypothesis, Discord, and Github set up; introduce yourself to the class in the social channel in Discord.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring Engagement</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 4.3 Measuring Engagement &amp;amp; Analytics Seneler, Cagla. 2017. The Effects Of Learning Styles And Cultural Background On Understanding The Information Architectures (IAs) Of Information Rich Websites Museums and the Web https://mw17.mwconf.org/paper/the-effects-of-learning-styles-and-cultural-background-on-understanding-the-information-architectures-ias-of-information-rich-websites/
Kelly, Lynda. 2016. The (post) digital visitor: What has (almost) twenty years of museum audience research revealed? Museums and the Web https://mw2016.museumsandtheweb.com/paper/the-post-digital-visitor-what-has-almost-20-years-of-museum-audience-research-revealed
Each reading is &amp;lsquo;seeded&amp;rsquo; with annotations by this week&amp;rsquo;s Discussion Leader; some of the annotations may contain video from the Discussion Leader directing you to pay attention to particular issues or ideas.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Pieces</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</guid>
        <description>In weeks 5 - 8, we are going to use Hypothesis as a platform to collaboratively explore the materials that you selected last week for your adventure.
In order to do that, you need to prepare your materials. I am giving you two weeks to prepare for this. Consider the amount of work as being similar to what you would do for a very good seminar presentation.
Goals for this week  Read and think about your selected materials carefully Prep them for the rest of us Improve your digital literacy  Listen Episode 3 of course podcast goes here</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare your pieces 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</guid>
        <description>In weeks 5 - 8, we are going to use Hypothesis as a platform to collaboratively explore the materials that you selected in week 3 for your adventure.
In order to do that, you need to prepare your materials. I am giving you two weeks to prepare for this. Consider the amount of work as being similar to what you would do for a very good seminar presentation.
Goals for this week  Read and think about your selected materials carefully Prep them for the rest of us Continue to improve your digital literacy  Listen Episode 4 of course podcast goes here</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Representation 4</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 2.7 Linked Open Data Oomen, Johan and Lotte Belice Baltussen. 2012. Sharing cultural heritage the linked open data way: why you should sign up Museums and the Web https://www.museumsandtheweb.com/mw2012/papers/sharing_cultural_heritage_the_linked_open_data
Newbury, David. 2017. Art Tracks: Using Linked Open Data For Object Provenance In Museums. Museums and the Web. https://mw17.mwconf.org/paper/art-tracks-using-linked-open-data-for-object-provenance-in-museums/
Tallon, Loic. 2019. Sparking Global Connections to Art through Open Data and Artificial Intelligence https://www.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Representations 3</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 2.5 APIs and Catalogues: Raw Data? Hogarty, Sarah Bailey, Keir Winesmith, Matthew Hrudka, Beth Schechter. 2015. Art + Data: Building the SFMOMA Collection API Museums and the Web https://mw2015.museumsandtheweb.com/paper/art-data-building-the-sfmoma-collection-api/
Morgan, Richard. 2009. What is Your Museum Good at, and How Do You Build an API for It? Museums and the Web https://www.museumsandtheweb.com/mw2009/papers/morgan/morgan.html
Moskvin, Illya, and nikhil trivedi. 2019. Building a Data Hub: Microservices, APIs, and System Integration at the Art Institute of Chicago Museums and the Web https://mw19.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The End</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read Nothing to read this week.
Do  Finish your case study. Submit both to the OTTGlam github repo (ie, use the form below to send me the link to your work) Write your Exit Ticket  With tech work, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come together in about 30 minutes, it won&amp;rsquo;t come in an hour. So take a break. Close the laptop.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>A clever bit of visual juxtaposition. Yes&amp;hellip;? Anyone&amp;hellip;?
(Photos by Scott Web https://unsplash.com/photos/ab80p262fFM and Ilya Pavlov https://unsplash.com/photos/OqtafYT5kTw )
HIST4916a Museums and Digital History How do museums and other organizations in the ‘GLAM’ sector (galleries, libraries, archives, museums) keep track of their collections? To what purpose? What might happen if we release these collections into the wild (via the internet)? If we mash these collections together what might we see, and why might it matter?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions text to be added
This course is a formalized exploration of these questions; I do not know the answers! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to figure these out with you.
Nb The process of teaching is also a process of collaboration between me and you. Sometimes -and we&amp;rsquo;re expecting this, you and I- things won&amp;rsquo;t work as we expect; tech might break; the world might impinge too much. We will adapt accordingly. Remember: the grade in this course is a function of your process and your evolution, so adapting and thinking through the implications of when things don&amp;rsquo;t go according to plan is, in fact, according to plan.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2.5. A GLAM Workbench</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2.5-glamworkbench/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2.5-glamworkbench/</guid>
        <description>Tangible Output of this Class Each of you will produce a computational notebook - a kind of website that has code within it that can be run, together with text and images describing what&amp;rsquo;s going on - that is focussed on the Ottawa GLAM scene.
All of these notebooks will be gathered together by me into an &amp;lsquo;Ottawa GLAM Workbench&amp;rsquo; (taking our cue from the inspiring work of Tim Sherratt and his GLAM Workbench on Australian and New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s cultural heritage).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. Course Schedule</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</guid>
        <description>** to be figured out **
 Jan 6 term begins  Select your topics &amp;amp; get your &amp;lsquo;chi&amp;rsquo; lab (Hypothesis, Github, Discord) set up
 Wk 1 - Jan 11  Foundations 1 Building 1  Basic digital skills     Wk 2 - Jan 18  Foundations 2 Building 2  Explore the OZGlam Workbench     Wk 3 - Jan 25  Representations 1 Building 3  Introduction to Jupyter Notebooks     Wk 4 - Feb 1  Representations 2 Building 4  National Library of Scotland Jupyter Notebooks     Wk 5 - Feb 8  Representations 3 Building 5  GLAMorous Ottawa Your first notebook SWOT of Ottawa: What kinds of things could you do?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. You are assessed on the following elements.
  Discussion Leaders. Each student will be responsible to &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; cetain readings. Page prep involves:
 Creating the Reading Overview: a brief overview page note attached to the assigned reading using Hypothes.is page notes Creating the Reading Pre-seed: at least five rich annotations on the assigned readings In the relevant week, when the other students read the papers, the student responsible for &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; will engage and respond to the annotations of their peers in such a fashion as to dig deeper into the topic at hand    Collaborative Readers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Library</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Jez Timms, unsplash.com
The possible readings are grouped under four broad headings. They represent merely a starting point, not a canon.
Foundations: Cultural Heritage &amp;amp; Information  in which we lay the groundwork for our understanding of CHI, its larger contexts, and what the major research questions are.
 1.1 Cultural Heritage and its Institutions   Abt, Jeffrey. 2008. ‘The Origins of the Public Museum’ in Sharon Macdonald, ed.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computational Notebooks List</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</guid>
        <description>Basic Skills We are going to use Jupyter Notebooks in this class. For a global overview of how Jupyter notebooks work and are used in humanities research, see Quinn Dombrowski&amp;rsquo;s lesson in The Programming Historian. The links below go to either live notebooks that you can work through, or guide you through some of the same steps that Dombrowski discusses, but with more detail.
  Working with the Command Line (PC) or Terminal (Mac)</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Discussion Leaders</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</guid>
        <description>The role of the Discussion Leader is to set us up for a deeper engagement with the task. You are the trailblazer, the guide, the scout, the point of first-contact, with a new and puzzling text. If there are two discussion leaders for a week, divy up the work between you equitably.
The seminar discussions all happen through the medium of Hypothes.is annotations: it is critical that you get these prepared in advance of your official &amp;lsquo;week&amp;rsquo; so that Collaborative Readers can respond.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Collaborative Readers</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not a Discussion Leader in a given week, you&amp;rsquo;re a Collaborative Reader, and your task is to enrichen our understanding of the material by engaging with the texts in a generous way. Following Kathleen Fitzpatrick, I understand &amp;lsquo;generous thinking&amp;rsquo; to work like this:
 Generous Thinking [begins] by proposing that rooting the humanities in generosity, and in particular in the practices of thinking with rather than reflexively against [emphasis added] both the people and the materials with which we work, might invite more productive relationships and conversations not just among scholars but between scholars and the surrounding community.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance on Building your own Notebook</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Your Notebook Is Due Before the End of Week 9 </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Github</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation.
Read completely through before trying to set things up.
 Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for your Case Study</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Your Case Study Is Due Before the End of Week 12 You will have submitted the link to your Jupyter Notebook at the end of week 9. If all goes according to plan, I will have bundled these altogether into a supporting website, the Ottawa GLAM Workbench (fyi, repo here) and used the My Binder service to make these live online, by the end of week 10. This gives you 2 weeks to create a &amp;lsquo;case study&amp;rsquo; document that can then be integrated into the workbench.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at [https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908](https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for the Exit Ticket</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/et-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/et-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Agus Dietrich, unsplash.com
Format The format of the exit ticket is up to you. Text, audio, video, multimedia: go wild.
Content Collect evidence detailing your journey in this course, and use the frame, &amp;lsquo;So what is Cultural Heritage Informatics, anyway?&amp;rsquo; to situate your response. You might want to go back to the course description to see what you now think of that description.
This evidence might be individual annotations (yours or someone else&amp;rsquo;s; remember, each annotation has its own permalink) that changed how you thought or make some argument you wish to engage with; it might be your own digital ephemera that emerges out of your contribution to our larger GLAM notebook infrastructure.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>