<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DHMuse on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DHMuse on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Before the class starts</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/get-started/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/get-started/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Do this the moment you see this:  Get Hypothesis &amp;amp; Join Our Class Group right now! Claim your topic as &amp;lsquo;Discussion Leader&amp;rsquo; by Saturday Join our Discord space right now! Set up a Github account if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have one.  Get Hypothesis &amp;amp; Join Our Class Group reate an account at hypothes.is:
Get the Chrome app or the Firefox bookmarklet:
Make sure you&amp;rsquo;re logged in:
Then join our HIST4916a reading group.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Beyond Visualization</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 3.3 Computational Creativity Compton, Kate. ‘Generominos’ http://www.galaxykate.com/generominos/
Weinard, Chad. 2019. Data as Medium. https://medium.com/@caw_/data-as-medium-361814dba6a9
Whitelaw, Mitchell. 2014. GENERATIVE HERITAGE - NOTES ON SUCCESSION the teeming void https://teemingvoid.blogspot.com/2014/12/generative-heritage-notes-on-succession.html
Woolf, Max. 2019. Experiments with Making Convincing AI-Generated Fake News https://minimaxir.com/2019/09/ctrl-fake-news/
Issue 44. Digital Creativity in Archaeology Internet Archaeology http://intarch.ac.uk/journal/issue44/
Each reading is &amp;lsquo;seeded&amp;rsquo; with annotations by this week&amp;rsquo;s Discussion Leader; some of the annotations may contain video from the Discussion Leader directing you to pay attention to particular issues or ideas.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Case Studies</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read No readings this week. However, look at the rich body of annotation you have. Use the readings and the annotations to help structure and support your Notebook case study.
Do  Write your case study that the other thing  With tech work, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come together in about 30 minutes, it won&amp;rsquo;t come in an hour. So take a break.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CHI &amp; Money</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 4.1 Budgeting and Bookkeeping Skinner, Sarah J., Robert B. Ekelund, and John D. Jackson. “Art Museum Attendance, Public Funding, and the Business Cycle.” The American Journal of Economics and Sociology 68, no. 2 (2009): 491-516. www.jstor.org/stable/27739781.
Toepler, Stefan. “Caveat Venditor? Museum Merchandising, Nonprofit Commercialization, and the Case of the Metropolitan Museum in New York.” Voluntas: International Journal of Voluntary and Nonprofit Organizations 17, no.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Engagement</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 3.1 Social Media &amp;amp; Audience Research, Ethics &amp;amp; Practice Byrd-McDevitt, Lori. 2019. “Reimagining Social Influencers through an Invitation Culture” in Humanizing the Digital https://ad-hoc-museum-collective.github.io/humanizing-the-digital/chapters/3/
Hooper-Greenhill, Eileen. 2008. “Studying Visitors” in Sharon Macdonald, ed. ‘Companion to Museum Studies’. Available online from Macodrum Library
Rao, Seema. 2017. Interstitial Spaces: Social Media As A Tool For Community Engagement Museums and the Web https://mw17.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Foundations of CHI 1</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 1.1 Cultural Heritage and its Institutions   Abt, Jeffrey. 2008. ‘The Origins of the Public Museum’ in Sharon Macdonald, ed. ‘Companion to Museum Studies’. Available online from Macodrum Library.
  Bennett, Tony. 1990. “The Political Rationality of the Museum,” Continuum: The Australian Journal of Media and Culture 2, no. 1 (1990), http://wwwmcc.murdoch.edu.au/ReadingRoom/3.1/Bennett.html.
  Daniel Buren, 1973.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Foundations of CHI 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 1.3 Collectors and Collecting   Bivens, Joy, and Ben Garcia, Porchia Moore, nikhil trivedi, Aletheia Wittman. 2019. ‘Collections: How We Hold the Stuff We Hold in Trust’ in MASSAction, Museums As Site for Social Action, toolkit, https://static1.squarespace.com/static/58fa685dff7c50f78be5f2b2/t/59dcdd27e5dd5b5a1b51d9d8/1507646780650/TOOLKIT_10_2017.pdf
  MacDonald, Sharon. 2008. “Collecting Practices” in Sharon Macdonald, ed. ‘Companion to Museum Studies’. Available online from Macodrum Library</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Measuring Engagement</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 4.3 Measuring Engagement &amp;amp; Analytics Seneler, Cagla. 2017. The Effects Of Learning Styles And Cultural Background On Understanding The Information Architectures (IAs) Of Information Rich Websites Museums and the Web https://mw17.mwconf.org/paper/the-effects-of-learning-styles-and-cultural-background-on-understanding-the-information-architectures-ias-of-information-rich-websites/
Kelly, Lynda. 2016. The (post) digital visitor: What has (almost) twenty years of museum audience research revealed? Museums and the Web https://mw2016.museumsandtheweb.com/paper/the-post-digital-visitor-what-has-almost-20-years-of-museum-audience-research-revealed
Each reading is &amp;lsquo;seeded&amp;rsquo; with annotations by this week&amp;rsquo;s Discussion Leader; some of the annotations may contain video from the Discussion Leader directing you to pay attention to particular issues or ideas.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Representation 4</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 2.7 Linked Open Data Oomen, Johan and Lotte Belice Baltussen. 2012. Sharing cultural heritage the linked open data way: why you should sign up Museums and the Web https://www.museumsandtheweb.com/mw2012/papers/sharing_cultural_heritage_the_linked_open_data
Newbury, David. 2017. Art Tracks: Using Linked Open Data For Object Provenance In Museums. Museums and the Web. https://mw17.mwconf.org/paper/art-tracks-using-linked-open-data-for-object-provenance-in-museums/
Tallon, Loic. 2019. Sparking Global Connections to Art through Open Data and Artificial Intelligence https://www.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Representations 1</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 2.1 Ownership and Authority Beaulieu, Anne, and Sarah De Rijcke. “Networked Knowledge and Epistemic Authority in the Development of Virtual Museums.” In Museums in a Digital Culture, edited by Van Den Akker Chiel and Legêne Susan, 75-92. Amsterdam: Amsterdam University Press, 2016. http://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt1s475tm.8
Lashaw, Christine and Evelyn Orantes. 2019. “Sharing Authority: Creating Content and Experiences” in MASSAction, Museums As Site for Social Action, toolkit, https://static1.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Representations 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Communities Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 2.3 Interpretation Anderson, Annie, and Ashley Rogers, Emily Potter, Elon Cook, Karleen Gardner, Mike Murawski, Swarupa Anila, and Alyssa Machida. 2019. “Interpretation: Liberating the Narrative” in MASSAction, Museums As Site for Social Action, toolkit, https://static1.squarespace.com/static/58fa685dff7c50f78be5f2b2/t/59dcdd27e5dd5b5a1b51d9d8/1507646780650/TOOLKIT_10_2017.pdf
Canning, Erin. 2019. Affect in Information Systems: A Knowledge Organization System Approach to Documenting Visitor-Artwork Experiences. Museums and the Web https://mw19.mwconf.org/paper/affect-in-information-systems-a-knowledge-organization-system-approach-to-documenting-visitor-artwork-experiences/
2.4 Online Exhibits: Cooked Data Drucker, Johanna.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Representations 3</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read 2.5 APIs and Catalogues: Raw Data? Hogarty, Sarah Bailey, Keir Winesmith, Matthew Hrudka, Beth Schechter. 2015. Art + Data: Building the SFMOMA Collection API Museums and the Web https://mw2015.museumsandtheweb.com/paper/art-data-building-the-sfmoma-collection-api/
Morgan, Richard. 2009. What is Your Museum Good at, and How Do You Build an API for It? Museums and the Web https://www.museumsandtheweb.com/mw2009/papers/morgan/morgan.html
Moskvin, Illya, and nikhil trivedi. 2019. Building a Data Hub: Microservices, APIs, and System Integration at the Art Institute of Chicago Museums and the Web https://mw19.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The End</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  this that the other thing  Read Nothing to read this week.
Do  Finish your case study. Submit both to the OTTGlam github repo (ie, use the form below to send me the link to your work) Write your Exit Ticket  With tech work, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come together in about 30 minutes, it won&amp;rsquo;t come in an hour. So take a break. Close the laptop.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>course promo video will go here
HIST4916a Museums and Digital History Department of History, Carleton University How do museums and other organizations in the ‘GLAM’ sector (galleries, libraries, archives, museums) keep track of their collections? To what purpose? What might happen if we release these collections into the wild (via the internet)? If we mash these collections together what might we see, and why might it matter? Where are the dangers - and to whom could it be dangerous?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions text to be added
This course is a formalized exploration of these questions; I do not know the answers! I&amp;rsquo;m excited to figure these out with you.
Nb The process of teaching is also a process of collaboration between me and you. Sometimes -and we&amp;rsquo;re expecting this, you and I- things won&amp;rsquo;t work as we expect; tech might break; the world might impinge too much. We will adapt accordingly. Remember: the grade in this course is a function of your process and your evolution, so adapting and thinking through the implications of when things don&amp;rsquo;t go according to plan is, in fact, according to plan.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. Course Schedule</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-schedule/</guid>
        <description>** to be figured out **
 Jan 6 term begins  Select your topics &amp;amp; get your &amp;lsquo;chi&amp;rsquo; lab (Hypothesis, Github, Discord) set up
 Wk 1 - Jan 11  Foundations 1 Building 1  Basic digital skills     Wk 2 - Jan 18  Foundations 2 Building 2  OZGlam Workbench     Wk 3 - Jan 25  Representations 1 Building 3  Introduction to Jupyter Notebooks     Wk 4 - Feb 1  Representations 2 Building 4  National Library of Scotland Jupyter Notebooks     Wk 5 - Feb 8  Representations 3 Building 5  GLAMorous Ottawa Your first notebook SWOT of Ottawa: What kinds of things could you do?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. Outputs to be added
  Discussion Leaders. Each student will be responsible to &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; cetain readings. Page prep involves:
 Creating the Reading Overview: a brief overview page note attached to the assigned reading using Hypothes.is page notes Creating the Reading Pre-seed: at least five rich annotations on the assigned readings In the relevant week, when the other students read the papers, the student responsible for &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; will engage and respond to the annotations of their peers in such a fashion as to dig deeper into the topic at hand    Collaborative Readers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started with Jupyter Notebooks</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/placeholder/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/placeholder/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Click title to see the full Post&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lorem est tota propiore conpellat pectoribus de&lt;br /&gt;
pectora summo. Redit teque digerit hominumque toris verebor lumina non cervice&lt;br /&gt;
subde tollit usus habet Arctonque, furores quas nec ferunt. Quoque montibus nunc&lt;br /&gt;
caluere tempus&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to Week 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/update2/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/update2/</guid>
        <description>(click the title to see the full post, not just this preview)
Welcome to Week 2! Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve got your virtual digital archaeology workspace set up, it&amp;rsquo;s time to go outside if you&amp;rsquo;re able and start recording materials. If that&amp;rsquo;s not feasible for you, the alternative assignment has you doing much the same work, but using crowdsourced photographs.
  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>And We&#39;re Off!</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/update1/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/update1/</guid>
        <description>(click the title to see the full post, not just this preview)
Welcome! Check your Carleton email account this morning for a note from me about getting started in the class.
There are no zoom meetings in this class (balloons, confetti, streamers fall from ceiling, much rejoicing, etc).
There is a discord server for a class social space and for video, audio chat &amp;amp; screensharing (which is useful when things go wrong and you want someone to look at what you&amp;rsquo;re doing).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at [https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908](https://github.com/shawngraham/hist3908.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>