<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DHMuse on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DHMuse on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo a combination of &#39;museum&#39; by iconsphere and &#39;computer&#39; by Chunk Icons, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar Concludes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</guid>
        <description>We conclude our discussion and this phase of the course. We transform that conventional model for a seminar from live face to face to a distributed, asynchronous model through collaborative reading &amp;amp; generous thinking
Goals for this week  Engage meaningfully with the discussion as prepared for you by your peers  Read Finish with William, Ryan, and Paula&amp;rsquo;s selections on the cyoa page.
Do Discussion Leaders: Discussion leaders will remain alert and will respond to posts and queries on their respective articles.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar Continues</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>We continue our discussion. We transform that conventional model for a seminar from live face to face to a distributed, asynchronous model through collaborative reading &amp;amp; generous thinking
Goals for this week  Engage meaningfully with the discussion as prepared for you by your peers  Read Continue with Patrick, Chantal, and Josh&amp;rsquo;s selections on the cyoa page.
Do Discussion Leaders: Discussion leaders will remain alert and will respond to posts and queries on their respective articles.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar Continues</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</guid>
        <description>We continue our discussion. We transform that conventional model for a seminar from live face to face to a distributed, asynchronous model through collaborative reading &amp;amp; generous thinking
Goals for this week  Engage meaningfully with the discussion as prepared for you by your peers  Read Continue with Niall, Sara, and Sian&amp;rsquo;s selections on the cyoa page.
Do Discussion Leaders: Discussion leaders will remain alert and will respond to posts and queries on their respective articles.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar is Go!</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</guid>
        <description>A seminar is a form of academic instruction, either at an academic institution or offered by a commercial or professional organization.[citation needed] It has the function of bringing together small groups for recurring meetings, focusing each time on some particular subject, in which everyone present is requested to participate. This is often accomplished through an ongoing Socratic dialogue with a seminar leader or instructor, or through a more formal presentation of research.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we begin to put into practice what we have heard and read and discussed
 Let&amp;rsquo;s make some magic!
Goals for this week  Discover the landscape of GLAM data in Ottawa Build your first notebook  Listen 5th episode of the podcast
Do  Follow along the Programming Historian Tutorial on visualizing data; there is a notebook you can launch; details here Write a notebook that grabs open data from CSTM and then visualize one dimension (column) of the data.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Our Own Adventure</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</guid>
        <description>I wanted this course to be about exploration and figuring out what this field, CHI, meant for this sector, GLAM. As we built this course in the fall, I realized I was making a huge mistake. It was too controlled. Too rigid. Too much about me. When we go to a museum, library, gallery, or archive&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s all about you, and your exploration. That&amp;rsquo;s how meaning emerges, right? So we tried to come up with a way for you to set the agenda and still meet the learning goals.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Data Wrangling</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  Cleaning data to make it useable Pushing data to the web  Listen 6th episode of the podcast
Do  [Cleaning Data with R]((https://notebooks.gesis.org/binder/jupyter/user/chantalmb-cleaning-data-r-a7752bq6/notebooks/clean-data-r.ipynb) Work with data in tabular format. For this, I&amp;rsquo;d like you to launch and follow along Melanie Walsh&amp;rsquo;s excellent four-part tutorial on working with tabular data in Python using the &amp;lsquo;pandas&amp;rsquo; data package. To launch the individual parts of that tutorial, look for the rocket ship icon and hit that (or download and run on your own machine).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we lay the groundwork for what this course will explore, its larger contexts, and what the major research questions are.
 Goals for this week  Get up and running with Hypothesis, Discord, and Github Understand what this course is about Start thinking about your goals for this course  This week is about reading the syllabus and understanding what is expected of you in this course. Get Hypothesis, Discord, and Github set up; introduce yourself to the class in the social channel in Discord.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Pieces</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</guid>
        <description>In weeks 5 - 8, we are going to use Hypothesis as a platform to collaboratively explore the materials that you selected last week for your adventure.
In order to do that, you need to prepare your materials. I am giving you two weeks to prepare for this. Consider the amount of work as being similar to what you would do for a very good seminar presentation.
Goals for this week  Read and think about your selected materials carefully Prep them for the rest of us Improve your digital literacy  Listen  Episode 3 Script/Transcript</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare your pieces 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</guid>
        <description>In weeks 5 - 8, we are going to use Hypothesis as a platform to collaboratively explore the materials that you selected in week 3 for your adventure.
In order to do that, you need to prepare your materials. I am giving you two weeks to prepare for this. Consider the amount of work as being similar to what you would do for a very good seminar presentation.
Goals for this week  Read and think about your selected materials carefully Prep them for the rest of us Continue to improve your digital literacy  Listen  Episode 4 Script/Transcript</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Some Other Visualizations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  Some more data visualization Other forms of &amp;lsquo;experiencing&amp;rsquo; data  Listen 7th episode of the podcast
Do  Make a new notebook (or modify an existing one) to load data from a new datasource. Visualize the provenance of your data using Leaflet (SG memo: Rachel Opitz workbooks) Or go for something complete different; try out some sonification on your data  I don&amp;rsquo;t expect you to do these on your own in splendid isolation; I also don&amp;rsquo;t expect that everyone will complete them.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The End</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  Finish crafting your notebook; I will collate these into a OttawaGLAM Workbench. Write up documentation for your notebook; the &amp;lsquo;notebook reflection&amp;rsquo; aka the &amp;lsquo;case study&amp;rsquo;.  Remember to consult the Guidance on Building Your Own Notebook and the Guidance for your Notebook Documentation, and the Sequence of Technical Work document. TALK about what you&amp;rsquo;re doing in Discord; ask for help from others or from me. I am happy for you to collaborate on both these tasks; just talk to me so that we can be clear about expectations.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4916a W21 Episode 1</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/transcripts/episode1/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/transcripts/episode1/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part One When I was a kid, I lived in the hinterland of Ottawa. One year, when I was in elementary school, I got selected to go to Ottawa to hear Marc Garneau speak at the Science and Technology Museum - he had just returned from his first mission on the space shuttle. It was very exciting. After the talk, I got separated from the rest of the group.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4916a W21 Episode 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/transcripts/episode2/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/transcripts/episode2/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part One So this week is an important week in the class. This is the week where you get to choose your own DHMuse adventure. And by choose your own adventure. I mean- you know the first time I did this class I had a huge list of readings that I wanted everybody to get through. It was in fact quite overwhelming. Both for the students and for myself.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4916a W21 Episode 3</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/transcripts/episode3/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:10:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/transcripts/episode3/</guid>
        <description>Transcript of this week&amp;rsquo;s podcast episode.
Part One Hey everybody, welcome to week three of the course. In this week, we have two major tasks ahead of us. This is the first of two weeks where you can prep your materials for our asynchronous seminar discussions coming up. It&amp;rsquo;s also the first week where you have an opportunity to start polishing or developing your digital skills in particular. We&amp;rsquo;re going to use what are called Jupiter notebooks, these are well, they&amp;rsquo;re interesting.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>A clever bit of visual juxtaposition. Yes&amp;hellip;? Anyone&amp;hellip;?
(Photos by Scott Web https://unsplash.com/photos/ab80p262fFM and Ilya Pavlov https://unsplash.com/photos/OqtafYT5kTw )
HIST4916a Museums and Digital History How do museums and other organizations in the ‘GLAM’ sector (galleries, libraries, archives, museums) keep track of their collections? To what purpose? What might happen if we release these collections into the wild (via the internet)? If we mash these collections together what might we see, and why might it matter?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions How do institutions in the GLAM sector use digital media to support their missions?
Do digital techs push us towards particular voices in GLAM materials?
Can/do digital techs in the service of GLAM harm different communities? And if so, how? And what can we do about it?
Where are the new frontiers in CHI and GLAM?
This course is an opportunity to explore these questions; I do not know the answers!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. A GLAM Workbench</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-glamworkbench/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-glamworkbench/</guid>
        <description>Tangible Output of this Class Each of you will produce a computational notebook - a kind of website that has code within it that can be run, together with text and images describing what&amp;rsquo;s going on - that is focussed on the Ottawa GLAM scene.
All of these notebooks will be gathered together by me into an &amp;lsquo;Ottawa GLAM Workbench&amp;rsquo; (taking our cue from the inspiring work of Tim Sherratt and his GLAM Workbench on Australian and New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s cultural heritage).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Course Schedule</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-schedule/</guid>
        <description>Check out the weekly instructions for detailed guidance for what you should be doing each week.
I estimate that the technical aspects of this course (the computational notebooks) will take about 17 hours over the duration of the course; see the weekly breakdown at the Sequence of Technical Work page.
TL;DR Remember to join our discord so we can actually have some social contact and remember that other breathing human beings are part of this course!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. You grade emerges from the following elements.
  Discussion Leaders. Each student will be responsible to &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; certain readings. Page prep involves:
 Creating the Reading Overview: a brief overview page note attached to the assigned reading using Hypothes.is page notes Creating the Reading Pre-seed: at least five rich/deep annotations on your chosen readings/materials (five total, not five per document) In the relevant week, when the other students read the papers, the student responsible for &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; will engage and respond to the annotations/responses of their peers in such a fashion as to dig deeper into the topic at hand see the guidance note for more information    Collaborative Readers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Library</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Jez Timms, unsplash.com
The possible readings are grouped under four broad headings. They represent merely a starting point, not a canon. This list is non-exhaustive, non-canonical, and is heavily tilted towards museums. Let&amp;rsquo;s fix that balance.
If a pdf is online, and you are able to open it in your browser, you should be able to use Hypothes.is on it. Sometimes you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to. In those cases, get in touch with me right away so we can figure something out.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Sequence of Technical Work</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/tech-req-at-a-glance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/tech-req-at-a-glance/</guid>
        <description>This page gathers in one place the sequence of technical work I want you to do or attempt.
You&amp;rsquo;ll see that some things are mission critical, while others are for you to push yourself.
You are not expected to do all of this work in heroic isolation, or to suffer through these exercises not understanding why something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Collaborate. Talk to each other. Ask for help. Share screenshots. Divy up the task.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computational Notebooks Resources</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</guid>
        <description>A list of interesting / useful notebooks and other things
Basic Skills We are going to use Jupyter Notebooks in this class. For a global overview of how Jupyter notebooks work and are used in humanities research, see Quinn Dombrowski&amp;rsquo;s lesson in The Programming Historian. The links below go to either live notebooks that you can work through, or guide you through some of the same steps that Dombrowski discusses, but with more detail.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Discussion Leaders</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</guid>
        <description>The role of the Discussion Leader is to set us up for a deeper engagement with the task. You are the trailblazer, the guide, the scout, the point of first-contact, with a new and puzzling text. If there are two discussion leaders for a week, divy up the work between you equitably.
The seminar discussions all happen through the medium of Hypothes.is annotations: it is critical that you get these prepared in advance of your official &amp;lsquo;week&amp;rsquo; so that Collaborative Readers can respond.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Collaborative Readers</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not a Discussion Leader in a given week, you&amp;rsquo;re a Collaborative Reader, and your task is to enrichen our understanding of the material by engaging with the texts in a generous way. Following Kathleen Fitzpatrick, I understand &amp;lsquo;generous thinking&amp;rsquo; to work like this:
 Generous Thinking [begins] by proposing that rooting the humanities in generosity, and in particular in the practices of thinking with rather than reflexively against [emphasis added] both the people and the materials with which we work, might invite more productive relationships and conversations not just among scholars but between scholars and the surrounding community.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance on Building your own Notebook</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Goal The goal of your notebook is to produce a computational document that engages with GLAM data from Ottawa. It would be helpful - but not required - to coordinate with your peers so that we have a wide variety of final notebooks. But even if two people created notebooks working with the same data, you would in all likelihood go about it in different ways, and so a user/reader would still learn from your example.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A simple scraper</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/notebooks/simple-scraper/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/notebooks/simple-scraper/</guid>
        <description>Right-click and save as the ipynb file.
 </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Github</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation.
Read completely through before trying to set things up.
 Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for your Notebook Reflection</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Goal The goal here is to create a kind of guide to a selected notebook that shows what the notebook can do. It walks the user through the notebook, how to use it, perhaps visualize results or ways to extend it, in order to suggest questions a user might want to pose, and why it might matter. That last point is the most &amp;lsquo;case study&amp;rsquo;-ish bit. By providing guidance on the &amp;lsquo;so what&amp;rsquo; question, you will engage with the literature or issues and provide context for non-dh-minded folk should take this work seriously.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publishing Data to the Web with Heroku and Datasette</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/datasette-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/datasette-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Prerequisites You need to have the following installed on your machine:
 Python. I recommend using Anaconda to manage all of your python related work. Get Anaconda here and get the 3.7 version. In the instructions below, you will also be installing Homebrew if you are on a Mac. Both PC and Windows people will need to install the command line interface (CLI) for Heroku. I recommend Mac people install Homebrew so that they can download the CLI from their terminal (also, lots of useful software is distributed using Homebrew).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Installing Jupyter</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/jupyter/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/jupyter/</guid>
        <description>Step 1 You need to make yourself familiar with the command line. There are many such tutorials out there; I encourage you to follow this one from Melanie Walsh&amp;rsquo;s Intro to Cultural Analytics class
Step 2 Anaconda is a package of different programming languages and utilities for &amp;lsquo;scientific computing&amp;rsquo;. Go to the installation page and find the version that is appropriate for your machine. Download and then run the installer.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>9. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/9-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/9-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at https://github.com/shawngraham/hist4916.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the Command Line on Mac OS</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/command-line-mac/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/command-line-mac/</guid>
        <description>Written Walkthrough If you&amp;rsquo;re brand new to this, I strongly recommend you start with watching the video first because it&amp;rsquo;s much more detailed. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re confident in your technical abilities or just looking for a refresher, then this written guide to the command line is for you!
Step 1: Accessing the Command Line To navigate the command line in macOS, we use Terminal, which is a built-in application.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Using the Command Line on Windows</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/command-line-win/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/command-line-win/</guid>
        <description>Written Walkthrough If you&amp;rsquo;re brand new to this, I strongly recommend you start with watching the video first because it&amp;rsquo;s much more detailed. Of course, if you&amp;rsquo;re confident in your technical abilities or just looking for a refresher, then this written guide to the command line is for you!
Step 1: Accessing the Command Line So first thing we&amp;rsquo;re going to want to do is actually open the command line so you can see what it is.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Intro to R &amp; RStudio</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/intro-r-rstudio/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/intro-r-rstudio/</guid>
        <description>Working with R R is a programming language designed for statistical computing and graphics creation, so it is excellent when it comes to analyzing large sets of data and creating visualisations from it&amp;ndash; which tends to be a big part of our work in digital humanities! The language was designed by and for statisticians and data analysts, thus many of those with little or no experience with programming find R a bit easier to understand and use than other programming languages.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>