<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>DHMuse on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in DHMuse on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 04:15:05 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar Concludes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eight/instructions/</guid>
        <description>We conclude our discussion and this phase of the course. We transform that conventional model for a seminar from live face to face to a distributed, asynchronous model through collaborative reading &amp;amp; generous thinking
Goals for this week  Engage meaningfully with the discussion as prepared for you by your peers  Read Dr. Graham will update this page to direct you to the appropriate materials for this week once we have settled our schedule.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar Continues</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/seven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>We continue our discussion. We transform that conventional model for a seminar from live face to face to a distributed, asynchronous model through collaborative reading &amp;amp; generous thinking
Goals for this week  Engage meaningfully with the discussion as prepared for you by your peers  Read Dr. Graham will direct you to the appropriate materials for this week once we have settled our schedule.
Do Discussion Leaders: Discussion leaders will remain alert and will respond to posts and queries on their respective articles.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar Continues</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/six/instructions/</guid>
        <description>We continue our discussion. We transform that conventional model for a seminar from live face to face to a distributed, asynchronous model through collaborative reading &amp;amp; generous thinking
Goals for this week  Engage meaningfully with the discussion as prepared for you by your peers  Read Dr. Graham will update this page to direct you to the appropriate materials for this week once we have settled our schedule.
Do Discussion Leaders: Discussion leaders will remain alert and will respond to posts and queries on their respective articles.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Async Seminar is Go!</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/five/instructions/</guid>
        <description>A seminar is a form of academic instruction, either at an academic institution or offered by a commercial or professional organization.[citation needed] It has the function of bringing together small groups for recurring meetings, focusing each time on some particular subject, in which everyone present is requested to participate. This is often accomplished through an ongoing Socratic dialogue with a seminar leader or instructor, or through a more formal presentation of research.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Building</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/nine/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we begin to put into practice what we have heard and read and discussed
 Let&amp;rsquo;s make some magic!
Goals for this week  Discover the landscape of GLAM data in Ottawa Build your first notebook  Listen 5th episode of the podcast
Do  this that the other thing  With tech work, if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t come together in about 30 minutes, it won&amp;rsquo;t come in an hour.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Choosing Our Own Adventure</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/two/instructions/</guid>
        <description>I wanted this course to be about exploration and figuring out what this field, CHI, meant for this sector, GLAM. As we built this course in the fall, I realized I was making a huge mistake. It was too controlled. Too rigid. Too much about me. When we go to a museum, library, gallery, or archive&amp;hellip; it&amp;rsquo;s all about you, and your exploration. That&amp;rsquo;s how meaning emerges, right? So we tried to come up with a way for you to set the agenda and still meet the learning goals.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Data Wrangling</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/ten/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  Scraping data / Cleaning Data Pushing data to the web  Listen 6th episode of the podcast
Do  Scraping Data Exercise Cleaning Data with Open Refine Publishing Data with Datasette  I don&amp;rsquo;t expect you to do these on your own in splendid isolation; I also don&amp;rsquo;t expect that everyone will complete them. Just push yourself until you get stuck, then talk about it / look for help in Discord.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/one/instructions/</guid>
        <description>in which we lay the groundwork for what this course will explore, its larger contexts, and what the major research questions are.
 Goals for this week  Get up and running with Hypothesis, Discord, and Github Understand what this course is about Start thinking about your goals for this course  This week is about reading the syllabus and understanding what is expected of you in this course. Get Hypothesis, Discord, and Github set up; introduce yourself to the class in the social channel in Discord.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare Your Pieces</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/three/instructions/</guid>
        <description>In weeks 5 - 8, we are going to use Hypothesis as a platform to collaboratively explore the materials that you selected last week for your adventure.
In order to do that, you need to prepare your materials. I am giving you two weeks to prepare for this. Consider the amount of work as being similar to what you would do for a very good seminar presentation.
Goals for this week  Read and think about your selected materials carefully Prep them for the rest of us Improve your digital literacy  Listen Episode 3 of course podcast goes here</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Prepare your pieces 2</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/four/instructions/</guid>
        <description>In weeks 5 - 8, we are going to use Hypothesis as a platform to collaboratively explore the materials that you selected in week 3 for your adventure.
In order to do that, you need to prepare your materials. I am giving you two weeks to prepare for this. Consider the amount of work as being similar to what you would do for a very good seminar presentation.
Goals for this week  Read and think about your selected materials carefully Prep them for the rest of us Continue to improve your digital literacy  Listen Episode 4 of course podcast goes here</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The End</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/twelve/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  Write up documentation for your notebook. that the other thing  Listen Listen to the final episode of the podcast
Do  Submit your jupyter notebook by logging it here at the end of this week. Write up a notebook reflection document that contextualizes what your notebook does, and how it fits into broader trends within the GLAM sector. See the guidance. This will be due no later than 10 days after the end of term, please.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Visualizing Data</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:10:37 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/week/eleven/instructions/</guid>
        <description>Goals for this week  Simple data visualization Other forms of &amp;lsquo;experiencing&amp;rsquo; data  Listen 7th episode of the podcast
Do  Try the Visualizaing Data with Bokeh and Python notebook (see here) or try sonification on your data Pull your notebook together.  I don&amp;rsquo;t expect you to do these on your own in splendid isolation; I also don&amp;rsquo;t expect that everyone will complete them. Just push yourself until you get stuck, then talk about it / look for help in Discord.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>1. Course Description</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:09 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/1-coursedescription/</guid>
        <description>A clever bit of visual juxtaposition. Yes&amp;hellip;? Anyone&amp;hellip;?
(Photos by Scott Web https://unsplash.com/photos/ab80p262fFM and Ilya Pavlov https://unsplash.com/photos/OqtafYT5kTw )
HIST4916a Museums and Digital History How do museums and other organizations in the ‘GLAM’ sector (galleries, libraries, archives, museums) keep track of their collections? To what purpose? What might happen if we release these collections into the wild (via the internet)? If we mash these collections together what might we see, and why might it matter?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2. Learning Outcomes</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/2-learning-outcomes/</guid>
        <description>Questions How do institutions in the GLAM sector use digital media to support their missions?
Do digital techs push us towards particular voices in GLAM materials?
Can/do digital techs in the service of GLAM harm different communities? And if so, how? And what can we do about it?
Where are the new frontiers in CHI and GLAM?
This course is an opportunity to explore these questions; I do not know the answers!</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>3. A GLAM Workbench</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-glamworkbench/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:38:51 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/3-glamworkbench/</guid>
        <description>Tangible Output of this Class Each of you will produce a computational notebook - a kind of website that has code within it that can be run, together with text and images describing what&amp;rsquo;s going on - that is focussed on the Ottawa GLAM scene.
All of these notebooks will be gathered together by me into an &amp;lsquo;Ottawa GLAM Workbench&amp;rsquo; (taking our cue from the inspiring work of Tim Sherratt and his GLAM Workbench on Australian and New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s cultural heritage).</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>4. Course Schedule</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-schedule/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:48 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/4-schedule/</guid>
        <description>Check out the weekly instructions for detailed guidance for what you should be doing each week.
TL;DR Remember to join our discord so we can actually have some social contact and remember that other breathing human beings are part of this course!
The first third of this course is about getting started and choosing your own adventure through the materials I have already gathered for you. You will do a deep annotation on the materials.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5. Assessment</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-assessment/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:38:59 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/5-assessment/</guid>
        <description>There is no midterm. There is no final exam. You grade emerges from the following elements.
  Discussion Leaders. Each student will be responsible to &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; cetain readings. Page prep involves:
 Creating the Reading Overview: a brief overview page note attached to the assigned reading using Hypothes.is page notes Creating the Reading Pre-seed: at least five rich annotations on the assigned readings In the relevant week, when the other students read the papers, the student responsible for &amp;lsquo;page prep&amp;rsquo; will engage and respond to the annotations of their peers in such a fashion as to dig deeper into the topic at hand    Collaborative Readers.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Library</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Jez Timms, unsplash.com
The possible readings are grouped under four broad headings. They represent merely a starting point, not a canon.
Foundations: Cultural Heritage &amp;amp; Information  in which we lay the groundwork for our understanding of CHI, its larger contexts, and what the major research questions are.
 1.1 Cultural Heritage and its Institutions   Abt, Jeffrey. 2008. ‘The Origins of the Public Museum’ in Sharon Macdonald, ed.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computational Notebooks List</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</guid>
        <description>Basic Skills We are going to use Jupyter Notebooks in this class. For a global overview of how Jupyter notebooks work and are used in humanities research, see Quinn Dombrowski&amp;rsquo;s lesson in The Programming Historian. The links below go to either live notebooks that you can work through, or guide you through some of the same steps that Dombrowski discusses, but with more detail.
  Working with the Command Line (PC) or Terminal (Mac)</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Discussion Leaders</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</guid>
        <description>The role of the Discussion Leader is to set us up for a deeper engagement with the task. You are the trailblazer, the guide, the scout, the point of first-contact, with a new and puzzling text. If there are two discussion leaders for a week, divy up the work between you equitably.
The seminar discussions all happen through the medium of Hypothes.is annotations: it is critical that you get these prepared in advance of your official &amp;lsquo;week&amp;rsquo; so that Collaborative Readers can respond.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Collaborative Readers</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not a Discussion Leader in a given week, you&amp;rsquo;re a Collaborative Reader, and your task is to enrichen our understanding of the material by engaging with the texts in a generous way. Following Kathleen Fitzpatrick, I understand &amp;lsquo;generous thinking&amp;rsquo; to work like this:
 Generous Thinking [begins] by proposing that rooting the humanities in generosity, and in particular in the practices of thinking with rather than reflexively against [emphasis added] both the people and the materials with which we work, might invite more productive relationships and conversations not just among scholars but between scholars and the surrounding community.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance on Building your own Notebook</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Your Notebook Is Due &amp;hellip;  notebook needs to be thoroughly commented, explaining what is going on in each cell, and explain how it is to be used.  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>A simple scraper</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/notebooks/simple-scraper/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/notebooks/simple-scraper/</guid>
        <description>Right-click and save as the ipynb file.
 </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Github</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation.
Read completely through before trying to set things up.
 Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for your Notebook Documentation</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Your Case Study Is Due at the End of Week 12 &amp;hellip;but I will accept it up to a week after the final day of the Winter term (which this year is April 14; thus, April 21st.)
I will bundle everyone&amp;rsquo;s notebooks and documentation together into a supporting website, the Ottawa GLAM Workbench (fyi, repo here) and used the My Binder service to make these live online.
Goal The goal here is to create a kind of guide to a selected notebook that shows what the notebook can do.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>6. Common Regulations</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-commonregs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/6-commonregs/</guid>
        <description>The following are the University regulations common to all History courses, that I am obligated to share with you. COPIES OF WRITTEN WORK SUBMITTED Always retain for yourself a copy of all essays, term papers, written assignments or take-home tests submitted in your courses.
PLAGIARISM The University Senate defines plagiarism as “presenting, whether intentionally or not, the ideas, expression of ideas or work of others as one’s own.” This can include:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>7. Contacting Dr. Graham</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-contact/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/7-contact/</guid>
        <description>Dr. Graham can be found online at
shawn dot graham at carleton dot ca
or on Twitter at @electricarchae.
He will be present in our class discord server every day.
If we ever get out of quarantine, and you&amp;rsquo;re in Ottawa, he often haunts the Library coffeeshop.
Online Office Hours Dr. Graham will be present in our Discord server every Wednesday from 1 until 3, and quite possibly the evenings too.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>8. Colophon</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-colophon/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/8-colophon/</guid>
        <description>As a general philosophy of learning, I do not aim for coverage. Rather, I am trying to help you learn the skills that you will need to uncover whatever aspect of method and thought that will help you with your research goals. A big part of that is trying to teach how to deal with what might feel like &amp;lsquo;failure&amp;rsquo;, on first blush. I want you to swing for the bleachers, and not to be afraid of whiffing on the ball.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>9. Reuse</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/9-reuse/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:39:06 +0900</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/docs/9-reuse/</guid>
        <description>Original content by Shawn Graham, is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.
Please feel free to reuse exercises in your own course materials, with a link back to the original page.
Corrections, modifications, additions are welcome; please fork, and then modify accordingly. Once you&amp;rsquo;re ready, make a pull request. The original repository is at https://github.com/shawngraham/hist4916.
All contributions will be duly credited.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for the Exit Ticket</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/et-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/et-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Agus Dietrich, unsplash.com
Optional This is an optional exercise.
Format The format of the exit ticket is up to you. Text, audio, video, multimedia: go wild.
Content Collect evidence detailing your journey in this course, and use the frame, &amp;lsquo;So what is Cultural Heritage Informatics, anyway?&amp;rsquo; to situate your response. You might want to go back to the course description to see what you now think of that description.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>