<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical Notes on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical Notes on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Computational Notebooks List</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</guid>
        <description>Basic Skills We are going to use Jupyter Notebooks in this class. For a global overview of how Jupyter notebooks work and are used in humanities research, see Quinn Dombrowski&amp;rsquo;s lesson in The Programming Historian. The links below go to either live notebooks that you can work through, or guide you through some of the same steps that Dombrowski discusses, but with more detail.
  Working with the Command Line (PC) or Terminal (Mac)</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Discussion Leaders</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</guid>
        <description>The role of the Discussion Leader is to set us up for a deeper engagement with the task. You are the trailblazer, the guide, the scout, the point of first-contact, with a new and puzzling text. If there are two discussion leaders for a week, divy up the work between you equitably.
The seminar discussions all happen through the medium of Hypothes.is annotations: it is critical that you get these prepared in advance of your official &amp;lsquo;week&amp;rsquo; so that Collaborative Readers can respond.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Collaborative Readers</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not a Discussion Leader in a given week, you&amp;rsquo;re a Collaborative Reader, and your task is to enrichen our understanding of the material by engaging with the texts in a generous way. Following Kathleen Fitzpatrick, I understand &amp;lsquo;generous thinking&amp;rsquo; to work like this:
 Generous Thinking [begins] by proposing that rooting the humanities in generosity, and in particular in the practices of thinking with rather than reflexively against [emphasis added] both the people and the materials with which we work, might invite more productive relationships and conversations not just among scholars but between scholars and the surrounding community.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance on Building your own Notebook</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</guid>
        <description>(click the title to see the full post, not just this preview)
blah blah</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for your Case Study</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</guid>
        <description>(click the title to see the full post, not just this preview)
blah blah</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for the Exit Ticket</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/et-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/et-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Agus Dietrich, unsplash.com
Format The format of the exit ticket is up to you. Text, audio, video, multimedia: go wild.
Content Collect evidence detailing your journey in this course, and use the frame, &amp;lsquo;So what is Cultural Heritage Informatics, anyway?&amp;rsquo; to situate your response. You might want to go back to the course description to see what you now think of that description.
This evidence might be individual annotations (yours or someone else&amp;rsquo;s; remember, each annotation has its own permalink) that changed how you thought or make some argument you wish to engage with; it might be your own digital ephemera that emerges out of your contribution to our larger GLAM notebook infrastructure.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>