<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="https://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Technical Notes on HIST4916a</title>
    <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Technical Notes on HIST4916a</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Original content by Shawn Graham licensed under a &lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;a rel=&#39;license&#39; href=&#39;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#39;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#39;Creative Commons License logo&#39; style=&#39;border-width:0&#39; src=&#39;https://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-nc/4.0/88x31.png&#39; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;Site logo &#39;archaeological information&#39; by corpus delicti, GR, The Noun Project.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Library</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/library/</guid>
        <description>Photo by Jez Timms, unsplash.com
The possible readings are grouped under four broad headings. They represent merely a starting point, not a canon.
Foundations: Cultural Heritage &amp;amp; Information  in which we lay the groundwork for our understanding of CHI, its larger contexts, and what the major research questions are.
 1.1 Cultural Heritage and its Institutions   Abt, Jeffrey. 2008. ‘The Origins of the Public Museum’ in Sharon Macdonald, ed.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Sequence of Technical Work</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/tech-req-at-a-glance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/tech-req-at-a-glance/</guid>
        <description>This page gathers in one place the sequence of technical work I want you to do or attempt.
You&amp;rsquo;ll see that some things are mission critical, while others are for you to push yourself.
You are not expected to do all of this work in heroic isolation, or to suffer through these exercises not understanding why something doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Collaborate. Talk to each other. Ask for help. Share screenshots. Divy up the task.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Computational Notebooks List</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/technotes-toc/</guid>
        <description>A list of interesting / useful notebooks and other things
Basic Skills We are going to use Jupyter Notebooks in this class. For a global overview of how Jupyter notebooks work and are used in humanities research, see Quinn Dombrowski&amp;rsquo;s lesson in The Programming Historian. The links below go to either live notebooks that you can work through, or guide you through some of the same steps that Dombrowski discusses, but with more detail.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Discussion Leaders</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/dl-guidance/</guid>
        <description>The role of the Discussion Leader is to set us up for a deeper engagement with the task. You are the trailblazer, the guide, the scout, the point of first-contact, with a new and puzzling text. If there are two discussion leaders for a week, divy up the work between you equitably.
The seminar discussions all happen through the medium of Hypothes.is annotations: it is critical that you get these prepared in advance of your official &amp;lsquo;week&amp;rsquo; so that Collaborative Readers can respond.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Collaborative Readers</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cr-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re not a Discussion Leader in a given week, you&amp;rsquo;re a Collaborative Reader, and your task is to enrichen our understanding of the material by engaging with the texts in a generous way. Following Kathleen Fitzpatrick, I understand &amp;lsquo;generous thinking&amp;rsquo; to work like this:
 Generous Thinking [begins] by proposing that rooting the humanities in generosity, and in particular in the practices of thinking with rather than reflexively against [emphasis added] both the people and the materials with which we work, might invite more productive relationships and conversations not just among scholars but between scholars and the surrounding community.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance on Building your own Notebook</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/nb-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Your Notebook Is Due &amp;hellip;  notebook needs to be thoroughly commented, explaining what is going on in each cell, and explain how it is to be used.  </description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for Github</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/github-guidance/</guid>
        <description>If any of the instructions below are unclear, annotate this page with hypothesis while being logged into our course reading group. If you spot someone asking for help and you can offer advice, respond to the annotation.
Read completely through before trying to set things up.
 Introduction Github is a code sharing website often used by digital historians. &amp;lsquo;Git&amp;rsquo; is a program that takes snapshots of the current state of a folder, and stores them in sequence, allowing you to revert your changes to an earlier state.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Guidance for your Notebook Documentation</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/cs-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Your Case Study Is Due at the End of Week 12 &amp;hellip;but I will accept it up to a week after the final day of the Winter term (which this year is April 14; thus, April 21st.)
I will bundle everyone&amp;rsquo;s notebooks and documentation together into a supporting website, the Ottawa GLAM Workbench (fyi, repo here) and used the My Binder service to make these live online.
Goal The goal here is to create a kind of guide to a selected notebook that shows what the notebook can do.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Publishing Data to the Web with Heroku and Datasette</title>
        <link>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/datasette-guidance/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>shawn.graham@carleton.ca (Dr. Shawn Graham)</author>
        <guid>https://dhmuse.netlify.app/building/datasette-guidance/</guid>
        <description>Prerequisites You need to have the following installed on your machine:
 Python. I recommend using Anaconda to manage all of your python related work. Get Anaconda here and get the 3.7 version. In the instructions below, you will also be installing Homebrew if you are on a Mac. Both PC and Windows people will need to install the command line interface (CLI) for Heroku. I recommend Mac people install Homebrew so that they can download the CLI from their terminal (also, lots of useful software is distributed using Homebrew).</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>